(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
3rd Anniversary Live
Connect: Addict
Lioness' Pride (remix ver.)
作詞/作曲：かめりあ　編曲：Hylen
Lyrics/Composition: Camellia  Arrangement: Hylen
白銀の獅子よ...
O silver-white lioness...
...駆けて 駆けて 駆け続けている
...running, running, continuing to run.
もう 振り返ることはないから
Because I'll never look back anymore.
百獣の王は
The king of beasts
99を信じ 空を睨んだ
believing in the 99, glared at the sky.
We have the pride.
and it's our reason of pride.
それこそが 私の誇り
That is exactly my pride.
どこか孤独の裏返しで
Somewhere, as the flip side of loneliness
ずっと一人なんだろうって思ってた
I thought I'd be alone forever
前だけ睨んで　ただ夢かけて
Staring only ahead, just chasing dreams
足跡見失って
Losing sight of my footprints
変わらない曇天　交わさない怒天
Unchanging cloudy sky, unexchanged thunderous sky
はぐれ山猫だって笑った
They laughed, calling me a stray wildcat
音の中だった　世界満ちて広げていく
In the sound, the world fills and expands
人たちの声や眼差しに　かざされて
Exposed to people's voices and gazes
私は変わりつつある　つぼみのライオンね
I'm a lion in the bud, changing
立って　今　爪を研ぐ
Standing up now, sharpening my claws
友の前歩くため
To walk ahead with my friends
真っ白い獅子は　群れて群れて群れを抱く
The pure white lion flocks, flocks, and embraces the flock
それが私を支えてくれるから
Because that's what supports me
純白の孤高を追って挑んでくれるものたち
Those who chase and challenge the pure white isolation
We have the pride in me, a lion's pride
それこそ私の誇り
That is my pride
怪我したふりして縄張りの
Pretending to be injured, of my territory
線を引いて無差別に引いてた
I was drawing lines indiscriminately
目指したものだけ　輝くものだけ
Only what I aimed for, only what shines
そしてただ迷うだけ　見失う軌道
And just getting lost, losing the orbit
解けなかった棘に　嫌気広がりゆく
Aversion spreads to the thorns I couldn't undo
私たちの熱　少しずつ帯びていくから
Because our heat is gradually building up
もし遠く遠く離れていても
Even if we are far, far apart
流微弱に向け微笑む
Smiling towards the faint flowing light
友に声届けるため
To deliver our voices to our friends
一輪の獅子は　咲いて咲いて咲き吠えたいのさ
A single lion wants to bloom, bloom, and howl
燃ゆる時を見守る人のために
For the people who watch over the burning moments
百獣の王は　一緒に一緒に咲き吠えたいのさ
The king of beasts wants to bloom and howl together
We can be the king of beasts together
白銀の獅子は　駆けて駆けて駆けつけ照らす
The silver-white lion runs, runs, and rushes to illuminate
もう不安に振り返ることはないから
Because I won't look back in anxiety anymore
百獣の王は　悠久を信じる力なのさ
The king of beasts is the power that believes in eternity
今なら前だけを　この夢だけを　見て走っていられる
Now I can keep running, looking only at this dream
後ろに大切な私たちの群れを纏うのだから
Because I have our precious flock behind me
We have the pride in me, a lion's pride
それこそ私の誇り
That is my pride
3rd Anniversary Live Connect: Addict
はい！ということで皆さん、改めてまして、ららーいおん！
All right! So once again, everyone, La-La-Lion!
ホロライブ5期生、獅白ぼたんです！
Hololive 5th Generation, Shishiro Botan here!
イェーイ！ということで...
Yay! And so...
今日はですね、ちょっと、まあ、遅れてしまったんですが、
Today, well, I'm a bit... well, late, but
周年記念、ま、3周年目終わりまして、
my anniversary, well, the 3rd anniversary has ended,
4周年目に突入するのかな？
and I'm entering my 4th year, I guess?
ということで、記念ライブを行わせていただこうかなと思います。
So, I'd like to perform this anniversary live.
今回のね、ちょっとコンセプトがあって、
I have a bit of a concept this time,
えー、ホロメンに歌ってもらいたい歌とか、
umm, songs I want Hololive members to sing,
一緒に歌いたいなと思った歌をゲストさんいっぱい呼んで、
and songs I wanted to sing together, calling many guests,
ちょっとね、披露していきたいなと思いますので、
I'd like to perform them for you,
ちょっと最後までたっぷり、いっぱいあるんで曲、
so, please stay until the end, as there are lots of songs,
よかったら見ていってください。
and I hope you enjoy watching.
ということで、もう早速いっぱいあるんで、いきましょう！
So, since there are many, let's get started right away!
しゅぴーん！
Shu-peen!
いつか君が示す場所へ
Someday, to the place you point to,
祈る声が木霊し続ける
my praying voice will continue to echo.
痛みこらえ進む意味を
The meaning of moving forward while enduring pain,
探す　今、加速してく
I'm searching for it. Now, it's accelerating.
―unfinished―
作詞：KOTOKO 作曲：八木沼悟志 編曲：八木沼悟志
—unfinished—
Lyrics: KOTOKO Composition: Satoshi Yaginuma Arrangement: Satoshi Yaginuma
きらめが溢れた
A flash of light overflowed
煩濁　停滞の世界
in this world of chaos and stagnation.
行く体　辿ろ
Following my moving body,
我の声も忘れてた
I had even forgotten my own voice.
絆を紡ぐ風に
In the wind that weaves bonds,
揺るがぬ自信探して
searching for unwavering confidence.
モノクロの朝が
A monochrome morning
不意に輝き始めた
suddenly began to shine.
変わらずにいてと願う事
Wishing for things to stay the same,
変わりゆく時に生きる僕ら
we live in a time of change.
本当の声を言えぬ夢を
A dream where true voices can't be spoken,
君と繋がった空へ響かせて
make it ring through the sky I'm connected to with you.
もっと強くこの両手で
Stronger, with these two hands,
涙すべて振り払えたら
if I could brush away all my tears...
今度こそは呟く「今」と
This time for sure, I'll mutter "now",
傷さえも無駄にしない
and I won't let even my wounds go to waste.
いつか君が示す場所へ
Someday, to the place you point to,
薄い羽が焼かれようとも
even if my thin wings are burned.
胸の奥で口を開く
Opening its mouth deep within my chest,
真実へと加速してく
accelerating towards the truth.
闇を見つめるの
I'm gazing into the darkness
虚空に据えた瞳
with eyes fixed on the void.
触れ合った肩が
Our shoulders touched,
わずか震えた気がした
and I felt a slight tremor.
弱気で消えそうだけど
I'm timid and feel like I might disappear,
守りたいもの確かにあるんだ
but there's definitely something I want to protect.
絶望の窓　不安定な空の中
Through the window of despair, in the unstable sky,
信じられるものはただひとつ
the only thing I can believe in is just one.
もっと深く感じさせて
Let me feel it more deeply,
動き出した心と心
the hearts that have started to move.
自分の目でそして触れて
With my own eyes, and by touching,
感覚を手に入れたい
I want to gain that sensation.
何を求め何を許し
What to seek, what to forgive,
いくつ抱え進めばいいの？
how many things should I carry as I move forward?
目覚めかけた可能性を
The possibility that's beginning to awaken,
手繰り寄せ加速してく
I'll pull it close and accelerate.
僕のために泣いてくれた
You cried for me.
その瞳を笑わせたくて
I want to make those eyes smile.
もっと近くもっと深く
Closer, deeper,
熱を帯び進化してく
taking on heat and evolving.
もっと強くこの両手で
Stronger, with these two hands,
涙すべて振り払えたら
if I could brush away all my tears...
今度こそは呟く「今」と
This time for sure, I'll mutter "now",
傷さえも無駄にしない
and I won't let even my wounds go to waste.
もっと早く君のもとへ
Faster, to where you are,
たとえ羽がちぎれようとも
even if my wings are torn apart.
歪む世界走り抜けて
Running through the distorted world,
感覚のその向こうへ
to the beyond of sensation.
真実へと加速してく
Accelerating towards the truth.
Jump up your brave
Pass in the sky
It's about of sensation
Connect Addict
作詞/作曲: DAIKI TSUNETA 編曲: MELRAW
Lyrics/Composition: DAIKI TSUNETA Arrangement: MELRAW
ラララライ ラララライ 誰も知らない 名も無い暇を駆けて行くの
Lalalalai lalalalai, I'm passing through an unknown, nameless moment
あの三日月へ手を伸ばして
Reaching out for that crescent moon
ラララライ ラララライ 君を知りたい 声にならない臆病な朝を
Lalalalai lalalalai, I want to know you, through the timid morning that remains unspoken
例え何度変えようとも
No matter how many times I change it
ラララライ ラララライ
Lalalalai lalalalai
ペースの合致とパチンと着慣れたその時
When our paces match and click perfectly into place
世界と育んでしまったみたいだ
It feels like I've nurtured a bond with the world
目に映る景色が悲しく笑うな
The scenery reflected in my eyes is laughing sadly
恐れず瞼を閉じてごらん
Try closing your eyes without fear
さあ皆さんこちらへどうぞ 鼓動の鳴る方へさ
Now everyone, please come this way, towards the sound of the heartbeat
踵打ち鳴らせどうぞ 心の踊る方へさ
Tap your heels, please, towards where the heart dances
蜃気楼に飛び乗って 逆さまの世界乗りこなして
Jump on a mirage and master this upside-down world
ラララライ ラララライ 止まない愛を知りたいと願うお呪い
Lalalalai lalalalai, a charm wishing to know an unending love
時を超えて 朝から夜まで
Across time, from morning until night
ラララライ ラララライ 君を知りたい 何一つ見逃さぬように
Lalalalai lalalalai, I want to know you, so that I don't miss a single thing
時は誰も待ってくれないのを
Knowing that time waits for no one
残酷な運命が 抗えぬ宿命が
A cruel fate, an unavoidable destiny
考える間もなく 足音鳴らして
Making footsteps without even a moment to think
前が見えなくたって 君を信じてみたいの
Even if I can't see ahead, I want to try believing in you
恐れずに一歩踏み出したら
If you take a step forward without fear
さあ皆さんこちらへどうぞ 鼓動の鳴る方へさ
Now everyone, please come this way, towards the sound of the heartbeat
踵打ち鳴らせどうぞ 心の踊る方へさ
Tap your heels, please, towards where the heart dances
さあ皆さんこちらへどうぞ 鼓動の鳴る方へさ
Now everyone, please come this way, towards the sound of the heartbeat
踵打ち鳴らせどうぞ 心の踊る方へさ
Tap your heels, please, towards where the heart dances
空飛ぶ鯨に飛び乗って 逆さまの世界踊り尽くせ
Jump on a flying whale and dance through this upside-down world
ラララライ ラララライ 誰も知らない 名も無い暇を駆けて行くの
Lalalalai lalalalai, I'm passing through an unknown, nameless moment
あの三日月へ手を伸ばして
Reaching out for that crescent moon
ラララライ ラララライ 君を知りたい 声にならない臆病な朝を
Lalalalai lalalalai, I want to know you, through the timid morning that remains unspoken
例え何度変えようとも
No matter how many times I change it
夢ならば覚めないで 現実なんてさ身も蓋もないから
If it's a dream, don't wake up, because reality is so blunt
時は誰も待ってくれないのを
Knowing that time waits for no one
蒼き炎
Aoki Honoo
作詞: 高橋洋子 作曲: 大森俊之
Lyrics: Takahashi Yoko, Composition: Omori Toshiyuki
年光を灯すすれば 儚い眠り
If the years of light are lit, a fleeting sleep
Schiarvest が
Schiarvest will...
気付き彷徨い踏み出した 確かな忍び合いを
Realizing, wandering, taking a step into a certain bond
Schiarvest が
Schiarvest will...
あぁ その背中は
Ah, that back...
羽をもぎ取られた跡がある
...has marks where the wings were torn off
小さな何かを信じて もう一度掴もう
Believing in something small, seize it once more
赤く燃える鼓動の火花 痛みそして揺れる
The red sparks of a burning heartbeat, the pain, and then it wavers
Schiarvest が
Schiarvest will...
拙い火を切り裂き 立ち笑うため高く
Cutting through the clumsy fire to stand and laugh high
Schiarvest が
Schiarvest will...
誇りを持ち合い 振り上げ
Holding pride together and raising it up
私の中で
Inside me
あなたの中で
Inside you
闇を切り裂くしているの
It's cutting through the darkness
No, そわない
No, it won't yield
No, 希望なんだせめて
No, it's hope, at least
君の微笑み 守るよ
I will protect your smile
奪われし明日へと続く世界
The world that continues toward a stolen tomorrow
導かれる Noble Flame
Guided by the Noble Flame
汚れなき夜の中 誰が許せるものか
In the pure night, who could allow such a thing?
それこそが Noble Flame
That itself is the Noble Flame
Oh その瞳は 何を捕え
Oh, what do those eyes capture
どこを目指すのか
And where are they heading?
小さな背中を信じて
Believe in that small back
もう一度進もう
And move forward once again
奪われてゆく一つずつの重さ
The weight of each thing being taken away
武器は捨てられない Noble Flame
I cannot throw away my weapon, Noble Flame
何のためにこの地を駆けて
For what purpose do I run through this land
今も守り抜くのか Noble Flame
And continue to protect it even now, Noble Flame?
凛として咲いたこの花は
This flower that has bloomed with dignity
悲しみ
Is sorrow
解けない魔法
An unbreakable spell
安らぎを遠ざける
That pushes peace away
Now そして今
Now, and in this moment
愛しさ故 傷に
Because of love, I'm covered in wounds
まみれた 孤独
In this solitary state
守るよ
I will protect you
安らぎを求めて
Seeking peace
それでいい
That's enough
希望なんだ
It is hope
せめて 君の微笑み 守るよ
At least, I will protect your smile
それでいい
That's enough
希望なんだ
It is hope
せめて 君の微笑み
At least, your smile
守るよ
I will protect
もし声が聞こえるなら
If you can hear my voice
渡り鳥 呼び満ちて
A migratory bird, calling out and filling the air
命が燃えている
Life is burning
はるかなる
In the distance
あの場所へ
Toward that place
美しい人
作詞：坂本真綾 作曲/編曲：菅野よう子
Beautiful Person
Lyrics: Maaya Sakamoto, Comp/Arr: Yoko Kanno
海鳴り
The sound of the sea
心が
My heart
恐れに 囚われぬように
So that it may not be trapped by fear
歌って
Sing
あなたの 生まれた 国の言葉で
In the language of the country where you were born
目蓋 見つめ合えば 目蓋の中
Eyelids, if we look at each other, inside our eyelids
同じ希望の灯をともしてる
We light the same fire of hope
まだ見ぬ地の花は
The flowers of a land yet unseen
まるで鈴の音の響き
Sound just like the ringing of bells
西へと向かう風に憧れよ
Yearn for the wind that blows toward the west
羽ばたいて
Spreading your wings
手の平 重ねて
Overlap our palms
痛み 映す 二つの 鼓動
Two heartbeats reflecting pain
教えて 二人を 隔てているものは 何?
Tell me, what is it that separates us?
ちやほや 時が来れば ちやほや
Adored... When the time comes, be adored
光の中 孤独は
In the light, loneliness...
温もりに 解けてゆく
...melts into warmth.
ほら 声が聞こえるなら
Look, if you can hear my voice...
渡り鳥を 導いて
...guide the migratory birds.
霧も夜も 嵐も
Mist, night, storms...
愛だけは 変えない
...only love will never change.
鳥が海を渡るように
As birds cross the sea...
人は人を知るために
...for people to know each other.
命が覚えている
Life remembers...
遥かなる あの場所へ
...that distant place.
あなたに 触れてほしい 憧れよ
I want you to touch me, my longing
抱き寄せて
Hold me close
届いて 私の 生まれた 国の言葉で
Reach me, in the language of my homeland
「メリドール 愛している」
“Melidor, I love you”
「メリドール 愛している メリドール」
“Melidor, I love you, Melidor”
この世界は非現実
This world is unreal
だが刷り込まれたビジョン
But it's an imprinted vision
無限連鎖 価値観を今
Infinite chain, now overwriting...
上書きする 天界のネイチャー
...values, the nature of the heavens.
御免な 神様は 目に映らない
Forgive me, but God is invisible
光速度で 支配し続けるならば
If He continues to rule at the speed of light
僕は 僕だけは
Then I, only I...
意識的で致命的なマイノリティでいい
...am fine being a conscious, fatal minority.
I can fly あの瞬間
I can fly, if that moment...
あの場面が 君にとって特別なら
...and that scene are special to you.
過去は離れてゆくもの 嘆かなくていい
The past fades away, no need to grieve
傷付くことの痛みより 大事な真相の全ての
Rather than the pain of getting hurt...
光が今 ゼロを生む
...all of the truth's light now creates zero.
Let's go to wonderful world
Let's go to a wonderful world
この命という無限
This infinity called life
まだ熱く灯らせて
Let it still burn hotly
二律背反 パラドックスさえ 限りなく
Antinomy... even a paradox, limitlessly
狭い世界線で欺き
Deceived in a narrow timeline
感情の支配
Controlled by emotions
非道秩序は
Outrageous order...
常識さえ塗り替えていくならば
...even rewrites common sense
僕の
Mine
僕だけの
Only mine
苦しみ その欠片さえ
Even those fragments of pain...
アルゴリズムのまま
...remain in the algorithm
I can fly 愛の標
I can fly, the sign of love
愛の言葉
The words of love
明確となるこの記憶を
This memory becoming clear...
二度と彼方に 置き去りにはしないから
...I'll never leave it behind in the distance again
いつでもまた君のそばに
I'll always be by your side again
隣り合わせその量子が
Those side-by-side quanta...
もつれ合えば
...if they become entangled...
ゼロになる
...they become zero
The past is worth visiting twice
まだ知らない新しい空
A new sky yet unknown...
世界線へ繋ぐのさ
...will connect to the timeline
I can fly...
あの瞬間
That moment
あの場面が
That scene
君にとって特別なら
If it's special to you
過去は離れていくものなんかじゃなくて
The past isn't something that just fades away
傷つくことの痛みより
More than the pain of being hurt
大事な真相の全ての
Every part of the precious truth...
光が今ゼロを産む
...the light now gives birth to zero
1,000,000 TIMES feat. chelly (EGOIST)
遠い宇宙の星
Stars in the distant universe
平行したまま
Remaining parallel
同じ夜を 願いながら見上げた
I looked up while wishing on the same night
全てを繋ぐ線が
The line connecting everything...
音を立てて崩れて
...crumbles with a sound
深く交わり合うほどに
So much so that they deeply intertwine...
夜明けを望んでいる
...hoping for the dawn
道なき道を進んでいた
Proceeding along a pathless path
声なき声を頼りにして
Relying on voiceless voices
名もなき詩を響かせた
Echoing a nameless poem
本当の祈りに今
To a true prayer now...
手を伸ばしてる
...I'm reaching out my hand
愚かしく麗しい人生が
Even if this foolish and beautiful life...
息苦しくても
...is suffocating
目標は高ければ高いほど
The higher the goal...
乗り越える意味があるから
...the more meaning there is in overcoming it
1,000,000/1でも
Even if it's one in a million...
「夢」が叶うなら
...if the "dream" comes true
僕は何度でも 何度でも
I'll go back again and again...
戦い続けていくから
...because I'll keep on fighting
主役がいなきゃ始まらないよ
It won't start without a protagonist
勝負をつけなきゃ終われないよ
It won't end without settling the score
僕と君の物語には
In our story...
誰も何も言えやしないよ
...no one can say a thing
ありきたりな世界を
An ordinary world...
かたやぶりな世界へと変えれる
...we can change into an unconventional world
一人じゃないから
Because I'm not alone
真っ直ぐな道を
Even when proceeding...
進む時さえ
...on a straight path
不安だけは
Anxiety alone...
消えずに付き纏ってた
...haunted me without disappearing
何時の間にか外から
Sometime from the outside...
心を固く閉ざし
...I tightly closed my heart
自分さえも忘れて
Forgetting even myself...
誓いを破っていた
...I was breaking my vows
渇いた笑いを浮かべて
With a dry laugh...
滲んだ涙を飲み干した
...I drank up my blurred tears
歪んだ想いを伝えたい
I want to convey my distorted feelings...
このまま失いそうだから
...because I feel like I'm about to lose them like this
狂おしく美しい絶望に
Even if I'm enveloped...
包み込まれても
...in a maddeningly beautiful despair
未来が暗ければ暗いほど
The darker the future...
辛く迷う日もあるけど
...there are days when I'm painfully lost, but...
100億年も前から
Since ten billion years ago...
「光」はあるから
...the "light" has always been there
僕は最後まで
So I will, until the end...
僕は最後まで希望を捨てずにいるんだ
I will not give up hope until the very end
真実は弱く儚くて 偽りは強く蝕むもの
Truth is weak and fleeting, while falsehood is strong and corrosive
君と僕の結末なんて 『白』か『黒』じゃ決められないよ
The end of you and me can't be decided as just 'white' or 'black'
ありふれてる奇跡や
Commonplace miracles and
まちうけてる運命でも
the destiny that awaits us,
一つじゃないから
it's not just one thing
一人で
Alone,
交わして
interacting,
二人で
as two,
合わせた
coming together,
あの日の約束を果たして...
fulfilling the promise from that day...
愚かしく麗しい人生が 息苦しくても
Even if this foolish and beautiful life feels suffocating,
目標は高ければ高いほど
the higher the goal is,
乗り越える意味があるから
the more meaning there is in overcoming it
1000000/1でも 「夢」が叶うなら
Even if it's only 1 in 1,000,000, if the 'dream' comes true,
僕は何度でも 何度でも 闘い続けていくから
I will keep fighting over and over again
主役がいなきゃ始まらないよ
It won't start without the protagonist
勝負をつけなきゃ終われないよ
It won't end until the showdown is settled
僕と君の物語には 誰も何も言えやしない
In the story of you and me, no one can say anything
ありきたりな世界を かたやぶりな世界へと変える
Transforming an ordinary world into an unconventional one
一人じゃないから
Because I'm not alone
決められたバイナリに従います 社交界の作法に溶け込みます
Following the predetermined binaries, blending into the manners of high society
それに価値器が満たされると信じてた
I believed that would fill the vessel of my value
舞踏会に溢れた息遣い その裏にありあまる思惑が
The breaths filling the ballroom, and the abundant motives lurking behind them,
重なり合って気づいたんだ 器の下は底抜けの状態だったんだ
overlapped, and I realized: the bottom of the vessel had fallen out
器を満たす意味は潰え 積み重ねたものなど疾うに
The meaning of filling the vessel has collapsed; the things I've built up are already gone,
無に帰した惨憺たる姿形と 現状抱える今日に
returned to nothing in a miserable form, within this current day I face
してやったという優越を かけらも奴らに与えない様に
So as not to give them even a fragment of the superiority of having 'done it',
流れた価値を仲間と取り返そう 自ら器を作っていこう
let's reclaim the lost value with friends, and build our own vessel
定石通りに動いてちゃ こんな人生つまんないな
Moving according to the standard moves makes this life boring
それならさ ギヤなんか壊して自分が望んだ結末をはめ込んでやれ
In that case, break the gears and slot in the ending you desire
ティーカップ裏に仕込んだ情報で 主役を演じていけ
With the information hidden under the teacup, go on and play the lead role
信じたものを守り抜くことができる この世界はわたしだけの人生だ
I can protect what I believe in; this world is my life alone
わたしだけの人生だ
It's my life alone
台本通りにかけられた言葉と 道行く人々の思想と顔
The words spoken according to the script, and the thoughts and faces of people passing by,
そのすべてが作り物であるとするならば
if all of that is a fabrication,
それすらも塗り替えてしまうような 誰よりも強いこの意思で
then with this will, stronger than anyone's, that can paint over even that,
すべて作り替え 誰もが想像し得なかった新たな未来へ
remake everything, towards a new future no one could have imagined
定石通りに動いてちゃ こんな人生つまんないな
Moving according to the standard moves makes this life boring
それならさ ギヤなんか壊して自分が望んだ結末をはめ込んでやれ
In that case, break the gears and slot in the ending you desire
ティーカップ裏に仕込んだ情報で 主役を演じていけ
With the information hidden under the teacup, go on and play the lead role
信じたものを守り抜く...
Protecting what I believe in...
守り抜くことができる
I can protect it to the end
この世界は
This world is
私だけの人生だ
my own life
私だけの
My own
人生だ！
life!
決められたバイナリに抗います
I'll resist the predetermined binary
社交界の作法に阿りません
I won't flatter the etiquette of high society
それで満たされる価値があることに気づいたんだ
I realized there's value in being satisfied by that
舞踏会に溢れた息遣い
The breaths filling the ballroom
その裏にあり余る思惑
The excessive intentions behind them
跳ね除けて残ったのは
What remained after pushing them away
人生真の面白さだ
is the true fun of life
POP TEAM EPIC
作詞/作曲/編曲：吟 (BUSTED ROSE)
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Gin (BUSTED ROSE)
見慣れた景色に瞳孔開いて
Pupils dilating at the familiar scenery
いつだって君は操作されている
You're always being manipulated
狂う狂うの輪舞結び合わせて
Tying together the madly spinning rondos
回る青色のカレイドスコープ
A spinning blue kaleidoscope
無意識バイアス　誰も知らない存在理由
Unconscious bias, a reason for existence no one knows
存在理由
Reason for existence
繰り返し　思い描くピクトグラフ
Repeatedly visualizing pictographs
破壊と創造の幾何模様
A geometric pattern of destruction and creation
打ち切りだ　立ち止まれば会えるよ
It's a cancellation; if you stop, we can meet
パラレルワールド　旅して
Travel through the parallel world
散りばめ願いに気づいて
Notice the scattered wishes
世界をリメイク
Remake the world
隙間もない　狭苦しい檻には
In a cramped cage with no gaps
粉々にして　取り返そう
Let's shatter it and take it back
無垢な産声に還れ　全部
Return everything to a pure newborn cry
何度でもディストピアを越えて
Crossing dystopia time and again
また会えるね
We'll meet again
次の世界で
In the next world
待ってるから
Because I'm waiting
まだ足りない　変幻自在なワンダー
It's not enough yet; an ever-changing wonder
思い描く連鎖　崩れてしまえ
Let the visualized chain crumble
意味がない
It's meaningless
君も忘れるだけ
You'll just forget, too
何度も手を振る私は
I, who waves my hand many times
懲りもせず　日々明けるんだ
Will bring the dawn of each day without learning
Bye bye
Lullaby
Bye bye しゃばい未来
Bye bye, pathetic future
毎回
Every time
群れない
Don't cluster
Bye bye しゃばいパラダイス
Bye bye, pathetic paradise
Bye bye
Lullaby
Bye bye しゃばい未来
Bye bye, pathetic future
デザイン
Design
変えたい
I want to change it
壊さなきゃ見れない
Can't see it unless you break it
未来干渉予防の
For future interference prevention
触れ、アレンジ
Touch, arrange
見ろ、システムは君を箱庭に閉じ込めた
Look, the system locked you in a miniature garden
ゆらゆらジェンダーパー
Swaying gender...
タイムシフト
Time shift
きらきらな鏡 ぶち壊して
Shatter the glittering mirror
新世界へ
Into a new world
ハイ上がれ
Soar high
思い描くピログラム
The programs you envision
破壊と創造
Destruction and creation
駆け巡る
Racing through
打ち切りの
Beyond the point
先でまた会えるよ
where things were called off, we'll meet again
パラレルワールド
Parallel world
旅して
Traveling
ちりばめた願い
Scattered wishes
引き連れて
Bringing them along
世界をリメイク
Remaking the world
ねぇねぇ二人とも！
Hey, you two!
何何？
What is it?
だるまさんが転んだをしながら
While playing Red Light Green Light,
この三年間でやったことない動きしよう！
let's do moves we've never done in these 3 years!
いいよ！
Okay!
最初はグー ジャンケンポン！
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot!
あいこでしょ！
One more time!
勝ったー！ねね鬼！
I won! Nene is "it"!
行くよみんな！
Here we go, everyone!
だるまさんが転んだ！
Red light, green light!
ラミィさんこっち来て
Lamy-san, come here.
お前動いてたぞ
You were moving.
一緒にやって。お尻振るだけ。
Do it with me. Just shake your butt.
せーの
Ready, set...
だるまさんが転んだ！
Red light, green light!
近い！
Too close!
あれ獅白、本日の主役。やほー！
Oh, Shishiro, today's protagonist. Hey!
駆けつけてきた。
I've rushed here.
ラミィも一緒に行くの。
Lamy's coming with us.
獅白も行くの？
Shishiro's coming too?
だるまさんが転んだ！
Red light, green light!
ラミィちゃんジャンケンポン！
Lamy-chan, rock-paper-scissors, shoot!
いつまでやるのそれ
How long are we doing this?
あいこでしょ！
One more time!
負けたー
I lost.
だーるーみー！
Red-light-green-light!
ちょっと待ったー！
Wait a minute!
今日何？後ろ見えないのこれ。
What's with today? I can't see the back.
それがライブですよ
That's what a live performance is.
ということで、わたくし獅白ぼたんの ちょっと遅れた三周年記念の
And so, I, Shishiro Botan, celebrating my slightly late 3rd anniversary...
おめでとうー！
Congratulations!
さっきさ、三年経って見たことない動きって言ってたじゃん
Earlier, you said "moves never seen in 3 years."
ねねちゃんの動き多分全部見たことある
I've probably seen all of Nene-chan's moves before.
見たことない動きがいい、これ今日。
I want to see moves never seen before today.
ラミィの動き、この高速走り
Lamy's movement, this high-speed running,
さっきやってたやつ
the one she did earlier.
あんま見ないかな、あんま見ないやつだよね
You don't see that often. It's rare, right?
万歩計めっちゃ回して走ってる人みたいになってる
She looks like someone running to max out their pedometer.
ポルポルのも見せておきたい
I want to show Pol-Pol's too.
3年、3年で初めて見る動き
A move first seen in 3 years.
こういう感じ
Something like this.
上下に揺れたほうがいいかも
Maybe it's better to bob up and down.
ふわっふわっとさせるの
Make it fluffy.
待機モーションなんだけどこれ
This is just an idle animation, though.
じゃあ獅白もせっかくなんで何か
Then, since you're here, Shishiro, show us something.
三年間やったことない... なんで可愛そうなの主役が！
Something I haven't done in 3 years... Why is the protagonist being treated like this!
そのまま上下に飛び跳ねたらカエルみたいで可愛いと思う
If you jump up and down like that, you'd look like a cute frog.
これ？
This?
汚ねぇんだよ
That's gross.
でもこれないわ！これないわ！
But this is unthinkable!
もっと不気味なコンボになってる
It's becoming an even creepier combo.
いや、見たことあるんだよなこれ
Actually, I think I've seen this before.
ねねちゃんのやつ全部見たことあるんだよな
I've definitely seen all of Nene-chan's before.
四人で歌って踊りましょう
Let's the four of us sing and dance.
楽しみ、何歌う？
Can't wait! What should we sing?
今から決めるの？
Are we deciding now?
私たちいつもブルクラ歌う人みたいになってるじゃん
We always end up as the people who sing Blue Clapper.
ブルクラ芸人です！
We're Blue Clapper comedians!
今日は三周年記念ってことで、みんなも三周年経ってるわけだから
Today is the 3rd anniversary, and since you all have been here for 3 years too,
かっこいい歌を歌いたいなっていうのがあって
I wanted to sing a cool song.
つまりかっこいいバージョンのブルクラ？
So, a cool version of Blue Clapper?
ヘビメタでやったでしょ！
We already did the heavy metal version!
なので今日はかっこいいやつをみんなで歌いたいなと
So today, I'd like for us all to sing something cool.
よろしくお願いします！
Please enjoy!
じゃあポジションついてみんな
Then, everyone, get in position.
その前にですね、私の新しい新曲が出るので
Before that, my new original song is coming out,
オリジナル曲の！
An original song!
そちらも歌わせてください
so let me sing that one too.
全部取っとくのMC？
You're hogging all the MC time?
そう言わないの、獅白の晴れ舞台として
Don't say that. It's Shishiro's big moment.
ぶっちゃけたこと言うと、喋りに来てくれるよなと思って
To be honest, I thought they'd come just to talk.
気軽に呼んだ
I called them over casually.
じゃあ獅白ぼたんの勇姿は後ろで見てて。
Then watch Shishiro Botan's heroic performance from the back.
その後みんな乱入してきて 歌うんだ！
And after that, everyone, barge in. We're singing!
あの個室残る？　あの個室。
Stay in that room? That room.
あの個室…
That room...
じゃあ、ししろんも…
Then, Shishiron too...
じゃあししろん…
Then Shishiron...
じゃ、ししろ君いってらっしゃい！
Well, Shishiro-kun, off you go!
いってらっしゃい！ 温めといて！
Off you go! Keep them warmed up!
温めて…温めといて…
Keep it warm... keep them warmed up...
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
というわけで、BLUE CLAPPER芸人でございますけれども、
And so, we're the BLUE CLAPPER unit members, but...
ししろさんの曲、どの曲かな？ みんな…
Which of Shishiro-san's songs will it be? Everyone...
どんな曲か予想してコメントお願いします！
Please guess which song it is and comment!
ししろぼたんの曲どんな曲かなってみんな、
Everyone is wondering which of Shishiro Botan's songs it'll be,
あ、楽しみだね、ししろぼたんの曲！
Ah, looking forward to it, Shishiro Botan's song!
お前ら！
You lot!
あ、じゃあこのあとも頑張ってください！
Ah, well, please keep doing your best after this too!
ししろぼたんの曲楽しみだね！ ブワァー！
Looking forward to Shishiro Botan's song! Whoosh!
Connect:Addict
作詞：RINA / 作曲：溝口雅大 / 編曲：酒井拓也
Lyrics: RINA / Composition: Masahiro Mizoguchi / Arrangement: Takuya Sakai
答え探し　彷徨っている
Wandering in search of an answer
教えてよ
Tell me
持て余した　僕の正しい
My "correctness" that I couldn't handle
伝い道
Path of transmission
ふいに一秒　導かれて
Suddenly guided for a second
鐘が響く
The bell rings
ひび割れた　液晶の中
Inside the cracked LCD screen
飛び込んだ　仮想的現実
I dived into virtual reality
目が眩むような
Dazzling, as if blinding
突然の閃光
A sudden flash of light
羽化する鼓動
A heartbeat that emerges
生まれ変わるんだ
I'm being reborn
純白のbutterfly
A pure white butterfly
自由にmidnight
Free in the midnight
何もかもが　全て揃う
In an era where everything
時代に
is available
巡り合う
Encountering
キミは唯一
You're the only one
僕を求めた
who sought me out
コネクトされる
Being connected
僕らの響き
Our resonance
昨日よりも上手く
Better than yesterday,
息ができる
I can breathe easily
気がする
I feel like
怖くない
I'm not afraid
「応答せよ、そちらはどう？」
"Please respond, how is it over there?"
感情が　コンバートして
Emotions are converted
文字となり　流れていく
into words and flow away
キミの世界　届けるハロー
Delivering a "Hello" to your world
聞こえますか
Can you hear me?
遠い街
A distant city
同じ歌で　眠りつく
Falling asleep with the same song
奇跡的現実
Miraculous reality
モノクロだった
It was monochrome,
見慣れた画面が
the familiar screen
いつの間にか
before I knew it,
万華鏡みたいだ
it was like a kaleidoscope
夢うつつaddiction
A half-dreaming addiction
魅惑のmission
An enchanting mission
ガランドウな
An empty
カラダを今満たそう
body, let's fill it now
煌めいて
Sparkling
誰も彼もが
Everyone and anyone
虜になる
will be captivated
妙薬のリップ
By the lipstick of a wonder drug
触れた瞬間
The moment we touched,
退屈も刺激を
even boredom will
帯びてゆくことを
take on a stimulation
キミに
to you
教えるよ
I'll teach
誰かが　放つノイズで
With the noise that someone emits,
羽が破れても
even if my wings are torn,
キミの
to
元へと
you
純白のbutterfly
A pure white butterfly
自由にmidnight
Free in the midnight
何もかもが　全て揃う
In an era where everything
時代に
is available,
巡り合う
encountering
キミは唯一
you're the only one
僕を求めた
who sought me out
コネクトされる
Being connected,
僕らの響き
our resonance
昨日よりも　キミを近くに
Closer to you than yesterday,
感じられる
I can feel you
抱きしめあって
Embracing each other
始まる歌 始まる鼓動
The song begins, the heartbeat begins
響き鳴り渡れ 希望の音
Resonate and ring out, the sound of hope
生きることを諦めないと
That I won't give up on living
示せ 熱き夢の 幕開けを
Show the opening of a passionate dream
放て この奇跡に 嘘はない
Let it loose, there's no lie in this miracle
RADIANT FORCE
作詞/作曲：上松範康(Elements Garden) 編曲：藤間 仁(Elements Garden)
Lyrics/Composition: Noriyasu Agematsu (Elements Garden) Arrangement: Hitoshi Fujima (Elements Garden)
その手は何を掴むためにある？
What are those hands for?
たぶん待つだけじゃ叶わない
Probably just waiting won't make it come true
その手は何を守るためにある？
What are those hands for protecting?
伝う熱は明日を
The heat that is transmitted will...
輝かす種火に
...become the spark that illuminates tomorrow
さあ新時代へ 引き金を引こう
Now, to a new era, let's pull the trigger
伝説の未来へとカウントダウン
Countdown to the legendary future
羽撃きは一人じゃない
The flapping of wings is not alone
過去を越えた先に
Beyond the past
創るべき歴史が
The history that should be created
咲き燃えてる
Is blooming and burning
絆 心 一つに束ね
Bonds, hearts, bundled into one
響き鳴り渡れ 希望の音
Resonate and ring out, the sound of hope
信ずることを諦めないと
That I won't give up on believing
唄え 可能性に ゼロはない
Sing, there is no zero in possibility
翔べよ この奇跡に 光あれ
Fly! Let there be light in this miracle
切り裂け まだ見ぬ日に行くために
Tear it open, to go to a day not yet seen
不可能なんて何一つない
There is nothing impossible
こんなに心強いことはない
There is nothing more encouraging than this
絶対 絶対 絶対 信じ合いぶっちぎる
Definitely, definitely, definitely, believing in each other and tearing through
たとえ闇に吸い込まれそうになって
Even if I'm about to be sucked into the darkness
涙さえも血に濡れて苦しくっても
Even if even my tears are soaked in blood and painful
帰る場所が待っている
A place to return to is waiting
集え 護れ 契れ
Gather, protect, pledge
勇気の結晶が
The crystal of courage
奇跡なんだ
Is a miracle
願い 祈り すべてを背負い
Wishes, prayers, carrying it all
本気を超えた本気の唄
A serious song that exceeds seriousness
痛みなんて何も怖くない
Pain is not scary at all
曝け出せ 震わせろ この身体
Expose it, make it tremble, this body
さあ 闇より 稲妻を
Now, lightning from the darkness
出会い 笑い合い そして 泣きじゃくり
Meeting, laughing together, and then sobbing
命の炎も 一緒に燃やして
Burning the flame of life together
五感の全部が叫ぶ
All five senses scream
愛と呼べるほどの
Enough to be called love
眩しく煌めいた
Dazzlingly sparkling
友の証
Proof of friends
絆 心 一つに束ね
Bonds, hearts, bundled into one
響き鳴り渡れ 希望の音
Resonate and ring out, the sound of hope
信ずることを諦めないと
That I won't give up on believing
唄え 可能性に ゼロはない
Sing, there is no zero in possibility
翔べよ この奇跡に
Fly! To this miracle...
光あれ
Let there be light
3rd Anniversary Live Connect Addict
獅白ぼたん
Shishiro Botan
風真いろは
AZKi
常闇トワ
大神ミオ
Kazama Iroha / AZKi
Tokoyami Towa / Ookami Mio
鷹嶺ルイ
角巻わため
星街すいせい
宝鐘マリン
Takane Lui / Tsunomaki Watame
Hoshimachi Suisei / Houshou Marine
雪花ラミィ
桃鈴ねね
尾丸ポルカ
Yukihana Lamy / Momosuzu Nene
Omaru Polka
制作：バルス株式会社
Production: VARK Inc.
カバースタッフ
COVER Staff